  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para><strong>Note:</strong> This version of the manual deals with
    the upcoming &shortversion; release, and is not usable with the
    current release. Please consult the documentation in the
    distribution itself.</para>

    <para>The <name>Python</name> standard library currently does not
    contain any platform-independent GUI packages. It is the goal of
    the <name>Anygui</name> project to change this situation. There
    are many such packages available, but none has been defined as
    <emphasis>standard</emphasis>, so when writing GUI programs for
    <name>Python</name>, you cannot assume that your user has the
    right package installed.</para>

    <para>The problem is that declaring a GUI package as standard
    would be quite controversial. There are some packages that are
    quite commonly available, such as <name>Tkinter</name>; but it
    would not be practical to require all installations to include it,
    nor would it be desirable to require all <name>Python</name> GUI
    programs to use it, since there are many programmers who prefer
    other packages.</para>

    <para><name>Anygui</name> tries to solve this problem in a manner
    similar to the standard <code>anydbm</code> package. There is no
    need to choose <emphasis>one</emphasis> package at the expense of
    all others. Instead, <name>Anygui</name> gives generic access to
    several popular packages through a simple API, which makes it
    possible to write GUI applications that work with all these
    packages. Thus, one gets a platform-independent GUI module which
    is written entirely in <name>Python</name>.</para>

    <para>To get the latest <name>Anygui</name> distribution, or to
    get in touch with the developers, please visit the
    <name>Anygui</name> website:
    <url>http://www.anygui.org</url>.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Design Goals</title>

      <para><strong>A</strong>. <name>Anygui</name> should be an easy
      to use GUI package which may be used to create simple graphical
      programs, or which may serve as the basis for more complex
      application frameworks.</para>

      <para><strong>B</strong>. <name>Anygui</name> should be a pure
      <name>Python</name> package which serves as a front-end for as
      many as possible of the GUI packages available for
      <name>Python</name>, in a transparent manner.</para>

      <para><strong>C</strong>. <name>Anygui</name> should include
      functionality needed to perform most GUI tasks, but should
      remain as simple and basic as possible.</para>

    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Warning</title>

      <para>The <name>Anygui</name> API is currently very much in flux
      as the <name>Anygui</name> team keeps experimenting with
      it. Because of that, incompatibilities may occur between
      releases. The current release (&longversion;) should be regarded
      as a prototype.</para>

    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Tutorial</title>

      <para>There is also a short tutorial available, which is
      included in the installation (<code>doc/tutorial.txt</code>) and
      is available from the website
      (<url>http://www.anygui.org</url>).</para>
    </section>
  </section>
